BRENTON HERSHNER

(513) 582-1366
BrentonHershner@gmail.com
Seattle, WA 98121
linkedin.com/in/brenton-hershner
github.com/brentonhershner

I started my career as a Mechanical Engineer and was promoted to Product Manager after earning my MBA. Despite my success, I always had a passion for code. I would often write small snippets of code to automate tasks. In March 2021 I decided to take a huge professional risk by quitting my comfortable, full-time job and joined a coding bootcamp. I loved every minute of the bootcamp. I woke up early to start coding before anyone else and was one of the last to sign off every night. Because of my performance, I was offered a role as a teaching assistant, which is extended to less than 10% of the students.

Rebuilding my career on a foundation of code really excites me! I've never felt better about the path in front of me and look forward to what the future holds.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATION	Software Engineering	Hack Reactor	Seattle, WA	2021
MASTER'S	Business Administration	Miami University	Oxford, Ohio	2019
BACHELOR'S	Mechanical Engineering	The Ohio State University	Columbus, Ohio	2008

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, C/C++ (Arduino), Swift (some experience)
Front-End: React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Babel, Webpack

Back-End: NodeJS, Express, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, NGINX

Development/Testing: git, GitHub, npm, Mocha, Chai, Jest, React Testing Library, CircleCI, K6, Loader.io

Deployment: AWS EC2 & S3, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Netlify

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

ToPics, A photo sharing social network for concerts and events.

github.com/brentonhershner/blue-ocean

- Served as the project architect, managed the GitHub repo, enforced Airbnb ESLint rules, conducted or delegated code reviews, and integrated continuous testing with CircleCI.
- Added batch photo upload to an AWS S3 bucket so multiple photos could be uploaded at once.
- Implemented the customer requested color scheme and a site wide dark mode using Material UI.
- Setup the express server written in NodeJS to serve static files and field API requests.
- Designed the API for communication between the browser and MongoDB database.

iRenta, A web app for rental property management.

github.com/brentonhershner/iRenta

- Dynamically renders content and manages state using **React**. Used **React Router** for fast navigation and preserves navigation history with the performance of a single page application.
- Incorporated Material UI to quickly develop a mobile-first, responsive user interface with site-wide dark mode.
- Implemented a server with **MongoDB** to be able to quickly iterate on data schema during development and rapidly change with the scope of the project. Currently switching this to a **MySQL** database.

Project-Catwalk, A responsive product page for an ecommerce web app. github.com/brentonhershner/Project-Catwalk

- Implemented React for dynamic rendering so a user could browse without reloading the entire site.
- Utilized the **styled-components** framework to uniformly apply **CSS** for a consistent visual customer experience with a singular design language. Added **SVG**s for crisp, non-rasterized graphics.
- Distributed the bundled code with an express server which also acted as a proxy to add authorization when making RESTful API requests to a backend web server.
- Tested using the **Jest** and **React Testing Library** to verify compliance to the customers business requirements. Automated testing with **CircleCI** which sped development and reduced bugs in production.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Immersive Resident, *Hack Reactor*

June 2021 to Present

- Instructed and guided troubleshooting to 500+ full-stack web development software engineering students.
- Held office hours to give one-on-one help to students' specializing in VS Code, testing, and SQL query issues.
- Facilitated stand-up meetings. Planed and ran social events and encouraged student engagement.

Mechanical Design Engineer then promoted to **Product Manager**, *OPW*

May 2013 to March 2021

- Granted two patents. Placed twice and won once in an annual innovation competition. Prototyped an Arduino based device
 to control servos based on input from a capacitance sensor and accelerometer. Successfully redesigned a soon to be
 released product to use fewer components which reduced the part cost by 65%.
- Managed products from conceptual stages to end of life. Launched a new product line for the European market. Led an
 effort to rationalize the product line by obsoleting poor performing products, resulting in a year over year profit increase
 despite lower revenue during the pandemic.
- Developed and distributed a dashboard of sales performance using Power BI generated with SQL queries.

Mechanical Engineer then promoted to Lead Electrical Engineer, Ferno-Washington

July 2011 to May 2013

- Designed electronic plastic enclosures, assemblies, and wire harnesses.
- Successfully reduced the electromagnetic interference (EMI) of strained electric motors to compliant levels for a medical device. Designed the CAN bus protocol between components and managed vendors' development to ensure functionality.